I realized it once again after Otoyan left.
二也离开后 我又一次意识到
He was the one
以前一直是他
who always cleaned up after me.
在帮我收拾烂摊子
ONE WEEK AGO
（一周前）
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Did I wake you?
吵醒你了吗？
Sorry. Good morning.
抱歉 早上好
Forget about "good morning."
有什么好的
Where did you go yesterday?
昨天你去哪儿了？
The business hotel in front of the station.
车站前的商务酒店
Ichiko, I'm planning on staying at a weekly hotel for two or three weeks.
小一 我打算找家短租旅馆 住两、三个星期
Why?
为什么？
What for? To get back at me?
为了报复我吗？
That's not why.
不是的
We need some time
我们需要
apart.
分开一段时间
To calmly think about things.
冷静一下 把事情想清楚
About ourselves
自己的事
and our marriage.
还有夫妻的事
-Tohko. -Yeah?
-姐 -嗯？
I'm sorry this is last minute, but let me stay at your place tonight.
抱歉 突发情况 请你收留我一晚
The weekly hotel near my office will have a room available tomorrow.
公司旁的短租旅馆明天才有空房
Sure, but--
可以 不过…
what happened?
出什么事了？
just the usual stuff between a husband and wife.
就是夫妻间的那点事
You don't need to tell me.
你不用告诉我
But is it really bad?
但真的很严重吗？
Mud-fight bad?
撕破脸了？
Don't tell me you might get a divorce.
可别告诉我你们要闹离婚
No.
没有
We're not getting a divorce.
我们没要离婚
Actually,
其实
I'm trying to prevent us from getting one.
我正努力避免走到那一步
You know, I like Ichiko,
我挺喜欢小一的
but sometimes marriages come to an end no matter what you do.
但有时无论你怎么做 都无法挽回婚姻
Hey.
话说
Why did you get a divorce?
你为什么离婚来着？
The two of you always looked happy.
你们俩看起来那么恩爱
I never told you?
我没告诉过你吗？
Let's see.
我想想啊
I think it started
刚开始应该是因为
when I got promoted and started making more money than him.
我升了职 赚的钱比他多了
It ruined the balance we had.
我们之间的平衡被打破
I was always on edge due to the extra work and pressure.
因为额外的工作量和压力 我总是很紧张
So he started getting annoyed about that.
所以他很不高兴
We started fighting more.
我们开始经常吵架
But you know, once we got past all that,
但过了那个阶段之后
we had already stopped talking to each other.
我们就不跟对方说话了
Towards the end,
到最后
we didn't even know what each other was doing
我们连对方的行踪
or how we spent the day.
每天在做什么都不知道
You had been together since you were 20, right?
你从20岁起就和他在一起 对吧？
He was always better than me at studying, had a better job and made more money.
一直以来 他学习比我好 工作比我好 赚的钱也比我多
And both of us got used to that.
我们俩都习惯了
But I think as we got older,
但随着年龄的增长
neither of us could accept the changes in the balance of our relationship.
我们之间的平衡发生了变化 我们俩都无法适应
Especially him.
尤其是他
He didn't seem like that to me.
我倒是没看出来
He was friendly and didn't act like a macho guy at all.
他总是很和善 看上去并不大男子主义
Feminine men have deep-rooted issues with their pride as men.
女性化的男人 男性自尊方面有根深蒂固的问题
Well, he has his reasons,
他有他的理由
but I don't care to learn about them now.
但我现在没兴趣知道了
Hey, Otoya.
二也
Don't you have any friends?
你没有朋友吗？
Someone you can tell everything to.
无话不谈的那种
I guess not.
好像没有
But I could tell Ichiko everything.
但我和小一能无话不谈
But aren't there things you can't talk to her about?
但也不能什么事都跟她说吧？
Yeah, you're right.
确实
It's nice that you could talk to her like a friend.
你能像对朋友一样跟她交心是很好
But I guess she really became your friend.
但她恐怕真变成你的朋友了吧
Nothing.
没什么
BASED ON THE MANGA "1122" BY PEKO WATANABE
（根据渡边平子同名漫画改编）
I'm back.
我回来了
Welcome back.
你回来啦
Are you okay? You don't look good.
你没事吧？脸色不太好
I feel much better after sleeping.
睡了一觉 感觉好多了
Thanks.
谢谢
Why don't I sleep with Hiro today?
要不今天我陪小宏睡吧？
Thank you.
谢谢你
Call me if you need me.
有事叫我
If you can't go to the wedding tomorrow,
如果明天的婚礼你不能去
I can go alone.
我可以一个人去
I think I'll be fine tomorrow.
明天应该没问题
Did you take medicine?
你吃药了吗？
No.
没有
Mitsuki.
美月
Are you pregnant?
你怀孕了吗？
This is just like when you had Hiro.
你怀小宏时就是这样的
I went to the hospital today to get tested.
我今天去医院查过了
They said I'm five weeks.
他们说已经有五周了
Do you know
你知不知道
who the father is?
孩子是谁的？
The baby is ours.
孩子是你的
How can you be so sure?
你怎么能这么确定？
He and I…
我和他…
We stopped a long time ago.
很久前就停了
Sleeping together.
没再上过床
I don't expect you to believe me
发生了那种事
after what I did.
我不指望你相信我
But it's the truth.
但这是真的
What do you plan to do?
你打算怎么办？
I want to have the baby.
我想把孩子生下来
After the baby is born…
孩子出生后…
I will have to raise it not knowing if it is really my child?
不知道是不是亲生 但我却得养他 是吧？
I'm planning…
我打算…
I won't earn as much as you,
我赚的钱不会有你那么多
but I plan to start working again. I've been job searching.
但我打算重新开始工作 我已经在找工作了
No.
不
Wouldn't it be impossible for you while you're pregnant,
如果怀孕生孩子
and even after giving birth?
你根本没办法工作吧？
That is what happened when you had Hiro.
生小宏时就是这样
Are you saying that
你这么说
because you think your job is more important than your family
是因为在你眼里 你的工作比家人重要
or taking care of our home?
比这个家更重要？
Don't change the subject.
不要转移话题
I'm not changing the subject.
我没有转移话题
You just throw everything about Hiro and your mom onto me.
你把妈和小宏的事都扔给我
Ignoring anything that is a hassle.
一味地逃避麻烦
What hassle? Aren't we a family?
什么麻烦？我们不是一家人吗？
Aren't we a family?
我们不是一家人吗？
I can't believe you can even ask me that.
你居然好意思这么问我
We are a family.
我们是一家人
Me taking on all of Hiro's care,
我一个人养孩子
keeping a relationship with a mom who urges me to join a weird religion,
一个人面对搞封建迷信的婆婆
is all for family.
我都是为了这个家
You choose to ignore it,
你选择了逃避
but every day is filled with annoying hassles.
但每一天都有很多麻烦事
Why are you looking away? Tell me.
你为什么不看我？说啊
Is this family just mine alone?
这个家是我一个人的吗？
It's your family too.
这也是你的家
Mitsuki, you…
美月 你…
How can you think about having another child
你已经有这么多事要操心了
when you already have so much to handle?
为什么还想要个孩子？
When it's the child of someone useless like me.
而且还是我这种窝囊废的孩子
Giving birth to Hiro,
生下小宏
raising him…
抚养他长大…
There are an endless number of things to worry about and suffer through.
让我操心、担忧的事数都数不过来
Even so…
即便是这样…
the happiness and joy I feel outweighs them all.
我感受到更多的却是幸福和快乐
When I found out I was pregnant again,
发现自己又怀孕时
I was scared
我很害怕
and anxious.
很焦虑
But it still gave me hope.
但这仍然给了我希望
Besides…
而且…
I don't think it's the child of someone who is useless.
我不觉得这孩子的爸爸是个窝囊废
I want this baby
正因为是你的孩子
because it's your child.
所以我才想要的
I need some air.
我出去透透气
Hey.
喂
Running away without a word again?
你又什么都不说 就要逃走吗？
Mama.
妈妈
Good morning, Hiro.
早上好 小宏
Good morning.
早上好
This…
这是…
You said you felt better after drinking seltzer when you were pregnant with Hiro.
你怀小宏时 说过喝苏打水会舒服些
You remembered.
你还记得
Thank you.
谢谢你
Let's go get changed with Mama.
小宏 跟妈妈去换衣服
Then after that, I'll give you a banana.
换完衣服 就给你吃香蕉
-Banana. -Yeah.
-香蕉 -嗯
Thank you all for making time to come celebrate with us today.
感谢大家在百忙中抽出时间 来参加我们的婚礼
Everyone, I just married
各位 我和我的心上人
my Madonna, Yui.
由衣小姐结婚了
As you already know,
你们很多人可能都知道
we are now a stepfamily.
我们是个再婚家庭
It was a long and difficult road…
这一路走来 真的很不容易…
Come here, Hiro.
来 小宏
-I'll do it. -No.
-我来吧 -不要
Hiro.
小宏
No. No.
我不
I am grateful to build a happy new life with the best partner in the world, Yui,
能和世上最棒的伴侣由衣 还有世上最酷的儿子大吾
and the coolest son in the world, Daigo.
从此一起生活 我感到非常庆幸
Hiro.
小宏
I am also grateful to our family, friends, and colleagues…
我也很感激各位亲朋好友…
No!
我不要！
-Stop right now. -No.
-快停下 -我不要
Go back right now.
快回来
-Stop making a fuss. -No!
-别闹了 -不要！
Be quiet!
别喊了
Shiro.
志朗
No. No.
不要
I'll take him home.
我带他回家吧
Hiro, let's go home.
小宏 我们回家
Go home.
回家
Mama.
妈妈
We're going home. Home.
我们回家 回家咯
Please give us your blessings. Thank you so much.
感谢大家的祝福 非常感谢
No. No.
不要
We're going home now.
我们这就回家
-No. -Hiro.
-不要 -小宏
-You don't want to go home? -No.
-你不想回家吗？ -不要
-Hiro.
-小宏
-Home.
-回家了
No. No.
不要
Mitsuki.
美月
Shiro.
志朗
I'll go with you.
我跟你们一起
No. No.
不要
Hiro.
小宏
We're going home.
我们回家
Let's go.
走吧
No.
不要
Later that night,
后来那天晚上
we had a fight, and my husband left the house.
我和我丈夫吵架了 然后他就走了
So it wasn't okay.
所以说不是没关系呀
Sorry. It was because of me.
对不起 都是我的错
No, it's not because of what you did.
不 这和你无关
It's a problem between me and him.
是我们夫妻间的事
Ichiko, are you feeling depressed?
一子 你难过吗？
I guess I'm a little sad.
我是有点难过
You even invited me out. Sorry for my mood.
难得你邀我出来 抱歉让你扫兴了
I know you're busy.
我知道你很忙
I was worried about you.
我放心不下你
I come here sometimes.
我有时会来这里
And it's close to my university.
而且离学校也很近
Oh, so you weren't curious?
你难道不好奇吗？
No.
不
It feels like I'm trespassing when I hear about your life.
听你说自己的事 让我有种侵犯他人隐私的感觉
So it feels kind of wrong.
感觉不太应该
It is like the more I know about your personal life,
我对你的个人生活知道得越多
the more real and human you become.
就越觉得你是个真正的人
What does that even mean?
你说什么呢？
So I'm not a real human?
我不是个真正的人吗？
But is it okay for you to meet your clients outside of the salon?
话说回来 在店外和客人见面没关系吗？
Yeah, it's okay.
没关系
You aren't a client anymore.
你已经不是客人了
And besides, I already quit the salon.
再说 我已经辞职了
-Right. -Yeah.
-对哦 -嗯
-It's huge. -Right?
-好大 -是吧？
And it was angry.
而且心情不好
-Angry? -Yeah, it was.
-生气了？ -嗯 生气了
They were fighting?
它们吵架了？
It was horrible of me to say you weren't a real human, wasn't it?
我刚说你不是真人 很过分吧？
I'm sorry.
对不起啊
Not at all. Don't worry about it.
没关系 别放在心上
But,
可是
it's what happens when money is involved.
金钱交易就是这样
You only demand what you want from the other person
直接从对方身上索取自己想要的东西
and skip the time and effort it takes to know the other person.
不用花功夫去了解对方
The time and effort it takes to know the other person?
花功夫了解对方？
Like knowing what the other person will never compromise on
比如去了解 哪些是他们不能妥协的事情
or what is important to them.
或者他们看重的事情
Doesn't the process of getting to know a person
了解一个人的过程
involve learning those things about each other and choosing what to share?
不就包括了这些吗？ 如何选择 如何分享
But doing that takes a ton of time and energy.
但这个过程要花费大量时间和精力
So I skipped all that
所以我直接跳过
to enjoy myself and have sex.
只要性爱 做那些让自己 感觉良好的事
And used money as compensation for your services.
然后用金钱作为服务的报酬
That is why I didn't really want to know about you.
所以我才不太想了解你
What?
怎么了？
It's nothing.
没什么
Most of my clients wanted to get involved in my private life.
大部分客人都想介入我的私生活
So this is new to me.
这还是第一次
Plus,
另外
I was thinking you're very honest.
我觉得你很直率
Am I?
是吗？
But I don't mean honest in a good way.
但不是在夸你
I know.
我知道了
You're saying my honesty is shallow and selfish, right?
你是说我的直率肤浅又自私 是吧？
I was basically saying, it was nice and comfortable for me
我刚才等于是在说 这对我而言比较方便
because I was paying you,
因为我付了钱
so don't tell me about your life since it's annoying.
所以别跟我说你的私生活 否则会很麻烦
Sounds pretty harsh when put into words.
这么说出来还真挺过分的
So, Ichiko…
一子…
Were you looking to build a relationship with your husband
你想花费时间和精力
that requires the time and effort needed?
和你丈夫建立关系吗？
Well, that was the plan.
我就是这么打算的
But what really happened was this mess.
但事实却是一团糟
You know, Rei.
礼
I have never regretted sleeping with you, no matter what I've said.
说了这么多 但我并不后悔和你发生关系
I'm really grateful to you.
我真的很感激
I'm glad I booked your services.
我很高兴当初选择了你的服务
Thank you.
谢谢
I see.
我知道了
Then I'm glad.
那就好
Ichiko.
一子
Do you have plans after this?
等会儿你有安排吗？
Want to have dinner with me?
想一起去吃饭吗？
Thanks.
谢谢
But I'm going home. I have work to do.
但我准备回家 还有工作要忙
Okay.
好吧
I guess there's no helping it.
那就没办法了
I know I have no right to feel hurt.
我知道我没有伤心的权利
ICHIKO AIHARA - HOW ARE YOU DOING, OTOYAN?
（相原一子 你怎么样了 二也？）
I'M GOOD. HOW ABOUT YOU?
（我很好 你呢？）
YEAH, I'M FINE. DO YOU HAVE TIME TO TALK TOMORROW AFTERNOON?
（我很好 明天下午有时间吗？我们谈谈）
Why exactly
我究竟
am I feeling so hurt?
为什么这么伤心？
SORRY, ICHIKO
（抱歉 小一）
I NEED MORE TIME BEFORE I CAN TALK.
（我还没有准备好）
CAN YOU WAIT A LITTLE LONGER?
（能不能再给我一点时间？）
What does he mean by "a little longer"?
什么叫再给点时间？
Until when?
还要多久？
But isn't he--
这家伙是不是…
…too naive? We're both hitting middle age.
…太天真了？我们俩都快步入中年了
Is he named after some sort of princess?
他当这是女性向游戏吗？
I thought about it.
我想过了
If I had to decide which is worse
如果要我说哪个更恶劣
between a husband having an affair with someone of the same age
是丈夫在妻子的默许下 和同龄小三搞婚外情
and with his wife's permission, or a wife paying for sex with a hot 20-year old,
还是妻子花钱买春 睡了个20岁的帅小伙儿
I'd say the wife paying for sex is worse.
我会说买春的妻子更恶劣
It feels much more disgusting.
更让人觉得恶心
Hey. Wait, Keikei.
等一下 惠惠
Didn't you say it was a great idea?
难道不是你说这是个好主意的吗？
And that I also have the right to sleep with other people?
说我也有权和别人上床？
No, no.
不是
The disgusting one isn't you.
我不是说一子你恶心
It's disgust for the lopsided power balance.
而是这种权利的不平衡
The unfairness of it.
这种不公平恶心
I gave you my support that time because I knew your situation.
我那时支持你 是因为我了解你的情况
Yeah, but you still told me to do it.
但你还是让我去做
But from what you said,
但照你这么说
does that mean Otoya would be okay if you had sex with that kid
如果你和那个弟弟上床 是因为你喜欢他
because you fell in love with him?
那二也就不介意了？
Well, no. I think he would really hate that.
不 我觉得他会很恼火的
Actually, even before thinking about Otoyan's reactions,
其实 哪怕不考虑二也的反应
I probably would never fall in love with a younger guy.
我大概也绝不会搞年下恋
Why? You were so excited about him.
为什么？你当时明明那么兴奋
I was excited because it was a fantasy.
因为那是一种幻想
When I imagine dating him,
若是和他谈恋爱
all I can think about is the responsibilities instead of the fun.
我满脑子能想到的 就只有责任 没有乐趣
I guess I was looking for a safe way to have fun within certain limits,
我是想通过金钱交易 找一种在一定界限内
using money as the means.
获得乐趣的安全途径
Wow, I am a horrible old lady.
我真是个可怕的老女人
Just living together with a partner you get along with is priceless.
能夫妻和睦一起生活 就已经很难能可贵了
It's extremely priceless.
特别难能可贵
I feel it keenly now that Otoyan left.
二也走了以后 我更是体会到了
Like how you would be grateful for good health after getting sick.
就像生了病才知道健康有多珍贵
Yeah, Otoya seems like a perfect partner.
二也看起来是个好丈夫
We always had similar beliefs and preferences,
我们的喜好和思想都很像
and we started to think alike the longer we were together,
在一起生活得越久 思维方式就越相似
as if we embodied "I am you and you are me."
就像“我就是你 你就是我”一样
You're turning into each other?
就像镜子里的自己？
But I think the other person needs to be different from you
可我觉得只有对方和自己不同
for you to feel attraction or lust.
才能产生恋慕和欲望
I think the eroticism is in being curious about the unknown,
我想情欲就是对未知的好奇
wanting to know more about him and wanting to get closer.
就是想进一步了解、接近对方
I think I get it.
我懂了
I think my sexual desire for Otoyan started to disappear
当我开始觉得和二也相处很自在
when I began to think it was so comfortable
我们变得越来越像时
that we started turning into each other,
我对他的性欲就消失了
even though we are two different and separate individuals.
尽管我们实际上是完全不同的人
Disappear, huh?
消失了吗？
And also your--
还有你的…
-calm sea. -Calm sea. Right.
-风平浪静 -风平浪静 对
Are you lonely now with Otoya gone?
二也走了 你觉得孤单吗？
Yeah.
孤单
Okay.
好吧
Here.
来
Your ketone bodies have increased.
你的酮体升高了
Are you eating properly?
能吃得下东西吗？
Well, sometimes.
有时候
It might be best for you to get hospitalized.
最好住院观察一下
I can't. I would like to avoid that.
如果可以的话 我不想住院
Then I'll give you an IV. You'll need to stay for a while, though.
那就给你打点滴吧 需要待一段时间
-Please. -All right. I'll get it prepared.
-拜托了 -好 我去准备
SHIRO, SORRY TO BOTHER YOU. I'M GETTING AN IV AT THE HOSPITAL.
（志朗 抱歉打扰你了 我在医院打点滴）
CAN YOU PICK UP HIRO? I'LL LET THE SCHOOL KNOW.
（你能去接小宏吗？ 我会通知学校）
OKAY BE SURE TO REST WELL
（好 你好好休息）
THANKS
（谢谢）
HERE'S HOW TO TAKE CARE OF HIM
（我会告诉你怎么照顾他）
Let's Yanyan together.
来和岩岩一起玩吧
LET'S YANYAN TOGETHER
（和岩岩一起玩）
Yanyan. Yanyan.
岩岩
Play the Yanyan video for him,
放岩岩的动画片给他看
give him a banana,
给他一根香蕉
and when he's in a good mood,
趁他心情好时
slip behind him and take off his clothes.
偷偷绕到他身后 帮他脱衣服
Yanyan.
岩岩
Hiro.
小宏
-It's a banana. Hiro. -Yanyan.
-给你香蕉 小宏 -岩岩
Yanyan.
岩岩
-Hiro, here's your banana.
-给你香蕉
"Slip behind him and take off his clothes…"
“偷偷绕到他身后 帮他脱衣服…”
That's impossible.
根本做不到啊
Giving him a bath is hard. But if he manages to take one,
让他洗澡很难 但如果真洗了
he'll panic if his face gets wet
他很害怕把脸弄湿
so wipe his face frequently with a towel.
所以要经常用毛巾擦脸
If you count while you wash off his hair,
洗头发时如果数数
he'll stay somewhat calm.
他会稍微平静一些
I'm going to count to five slowly. It will be over in five.
我会慢慢数到五 然后就洗好了
Okay. Here we go.
好 开始
One.
一
Two.
二
Hey. Stop that!
别闹
Mama.
妈妈
-Hiro. Time to sleep. -Mama.
-小宏 该睡觉了 -妈妈
He'll cry and roll around,
他会哭闹 会翻来覆去
but he'll eventually fall asleep.
但最终会睡着
He's not sleeping at all.
根本不睡啊
Mama.
妈妈
Hiro.
小宏
Look, it's Yanyan. Yanyan.
看 是岩岩哦
-Yanyan? -Yeah, Yanyan.
-岩岩？ -嗯 岩岩
Hiro, show Papa which one is Yanyan.
小宏 告诉爸爸哪个是岩岩
-Yanyan. -This is Yanyan.
-岩岩 -这个是岩岩
LOST YANYAN
（《迷路的岩岩》）
Want to read it?
我念给你听？
"Yanyan is lost in space."
“岩岩在太空中迷路了”
Yanyan.
岩岩
This is Yanyan?
这是岩岩？
"Space is a much bigger star than the Earth.
“太空比地球大很多
One day, Yanyan--"
有一天 岩岩…”
Yanyan.
岩岩
-Is this Yanyan? -Yeah.
-这是岩岩？ -嗯
Is he an alien? Is Yanyan an alien?
他是个外星人吗？岩岩是外星人？
You don't know, huh?
你不知道？
"One day, Yanyan met Yurayura
“有一天 岩岩遇见了揺揺
who fell from space.
揺揺从太空掉下来
I am also searching for space.
我也在寻找太空
Can I join you?
我能和你一起吗？
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
我们走吧
Hello?"
你好呀？”
Yanyan.
岩岩
This is Yanyan? He's cute.
这是岩岩？他真可爱
Welcome back.
你回来了
Thanks.
我回来了
Is Hiro sleeping?
小宏睡了吗？
He just fell asleep.
他刚睡着
Thank you.
谢谢你
How are you feeling?
你感觉怎么样？
Much better after getting the IV.
打过点滴好多了
You're tired, right?
你累了吧？
He panicked because I wasn't Mama.
因为我不是妈妈 他慌了
Of course.
是啊
So you couldn't bathe him?
所以没能洗澡？
I did.
洗了
But he cried.
但他哭了
Really?
真的？
Somehow,
也不知怎的
I managed to do it by following your instructions.
照你说的做 就真做到了
Okay.
好吧
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
Mitsuki?
美月？
It's been three days…
他已经三天…
since he took a bath.
没洗澡了
I couldn't give him a bath at all.
我完全做不到
You can't help it.
那也没办法
You have bad morning sickness.
你孕吐得厉害
It's not only the bath.
不光是洗澡
I couldn't stop him from eating snacks instead of meals.
他不吃饭 光吃零食 我也没办法
And I kept playing videos for him to watch.
而且我一直放动画片给他看
At night, he kept being fussy and refused to sleep.
晚上 他闹得厉害 不肯睡觉
So it gave me such a headache that I couldn't take it.
让我头疼得受不了
Yesterday…
昨天…
I hit…
我对小宏…
Hiro.
动手了
It wasn't the first time, either.
而且不是第一次
You didn't know, did you?
你不知道吧？
Hiro's having such a hard time,
小宏现在这么难带
but I can't even take care of myself when I'm feeling like this.
可我连自己都照顾不好
But still…
即便如此…
why did I say I want to have this baby?
我还说要生下这个孩子 到底是怎么想的？
When I'm already like this?
明明都已经这样了
I wonder if I really am an idiot.
我果然是个大傻瓜
Mitsuki.
美月
Thank you for looking after him by yourself all this time.
谢谢你一直以来独自照顾小宏
Sorry.
对不起
I thought I needed to be honest with you.
我必须对你说实话
As Hiro started getting older…
随着小宏年龄的增长
we started to see that his development wasn't normal.
我们逐渐意识到 他和同龄孩子不一样
But I didn't want to accept that.
但我不想承认
So I think I turned a blind eye and ignored the situation.
于是我视而不见 逃避问题
I stubbornly believed my son wasn't like that.
我固执地相信 我的孩子不会是这样的
But it could also be because…
但也有可能是因为…
I was more concerned about how I looked to other people…
我更担心别人会怎么看我…
than about Hiro's life.
而不是担心小宏
It was my fault you had an affair.
你出轨是我的错
Since I kept saying you were in charge of the home…
因为我一直说 家里的事都该由你负责…
like it was a normal thing.
就好像这是理所当然的
Didn't you say that, Mitsuki?
你不是说过吗 美月？
That we both have to change.
说我们都得改变
It's only a little bit, but I think…
虽然这点改变微不足道…
I finally understand what your words meant.
但我终于懂你的意思了
You're probably thinking, "What the hell is he saying now?"
你可能在想：“他到底在说什么？”
Shiro.
志朗
To be honest, I'm still not confident.
老实说 我还是没什么信心
But if you'll forgive me,
但如果你能原谅我
if it's not too late…
如果还来得及…
I want to accept them.
我想好好接受他们
Everything about Hiro
接受小宏的一切
and the baby you're having.
还有你肚子里的孩子
Will you forgive me?
你能原谅我吗？
Thank you.
谢谢你
-It gets stuck here. -That's right.
-这里卡住了 -对
It opens up completely when you pull the bottom out like this.
像这样把下面拽出来 就能打开了
You're right.
真的呢
Hello, Mother? What's the matter?
喂？妈妈？出什么事了？
I'm so sorry, Otoya.
对不起 二也
I tried calling Ichiko, but she wouldn't answer.
我打给一子 但她不接电话
She might be in a meeting. Why did you call?
她可能在见客户 您有什么事？
My kettle isn't working, and my phone is acting weird.
我的水壶坏了 手机也很奇怪
Everything keeps disappearing.
东西总是消失不见
You might need a new kettle.
您可能需要一个新水壶
Do you know what company you got your smartphone from?
您知道手机是哪家公司的吗？
What company?
哪家公司？
I have no idea.
我不知道
Okay, I'll ask Ichiko.
好 我会问小一的
Don't worry, I'll get it all fixed.
放心 我会处理的
First, I'll send you a new kettle.
先给您送一个新水壶过去
I'll ask the store about your phone and call you back.
我会去店里查一下您的手机 然后再联系您
Thank you.
谢谢
I'm so sorry to bother you when you're so busy.
抱歉打扰了 你工作那么忙
It's not a problem. I'll call you later.
没关系 我晚点再打给您
Yes, thank you.
好 谢谢
Bye.
再见
So it's like a drawstring purse.
就像抽绳包一样
The handle is very nice.
把手很好看
YOUR MOTHER CALLED SAYING HER KETTLE BROKE
（你妈妈打电话说水壶坏了）
SO I SENT HER THIS ONE
（所以我送了这个过去）
THANK YOU! IT'S SO FANCY!
（谢谢！好高级！）
Ichiko hasn't messaged me
自从四天前这条短信之后
since this last one four days ago.
小一就没联系过我
Thank you for waiting. Here is your highball.
久等了 这是您的海波鸡尾酒
Thank you.
谢谢
Don't tell me--
难不成…
she's been having sex with that good-looking guy?
她这些天都在和那小白脸上床？
She's too busy having sex?
忙着和他滚床单？
But,
可是
can I even say anything about her sex life
我有资格干涉她的性生活吗？
after getting mad and leaving the house like that?
毕竟是我发了脾气 离家出走
No. But I'm still her husband.
不对 我还是她的丈夫呀
Wait, can't I just call her?
等等 给她打个电话不就行了？
Come on. I can do it.
对啊 可以打电话
Hello?
喂？
Hello? Ichiko?
喂？小一？
Sor--
对不…
What?
什么？
Is she--
难道她…
really going at it right now?
真的在滚床单？
SORRY, I HAVE A COLD
（对不起 我感冒了）
BY COLD, I MEAN WHOOPING COUGH SO I CAN'T TALK
（咳得特别厉害 嗓子都哑了）
I'M COMING HOME FOR A BIT
（我要回趟家）
Excuse me. The check, please.
劳驾 买单
Okay.
好
I'm home.
我回来了
Ichiko, you need to sleep.
小一 你该去睡觉
I know you have work, but still.
我知道你有工作要忙 那也不能这样
I'M SORRY I MADE A MESS!!
（对不起 我把家里弄得乱七八糟）
It's okay. It's milder than I imagined.
没关系 比我想象的好点
Ichiko, want some noodle soup?
小一 我帮你煮碗面条吧？
Thank you.
谢谢
I bought cough drops.
我买了润喉糖
Okay.
好
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
Ichiko.
小一
You can keep eating, but can I say something?
你吃你的 我说几句行吗？
I'm sorry we can't have a discussion.
对不起 只有我单方面能发言
But first,
但首先
I apologize for leaving like that.
之前那样离开是我不好
I know I don't have any right to blame you.
我知道我没资格怪你
But I couldn't accept what you did, got emotional and ran away.
但我无法面对 所以情绪激动 然后一走了之
I thought about it when I was alone.
我一个人时好好想过了
Didn't we get married
我们当初结婚
because we want to live happily with each other as partners,
不就是因为无论如何都想和对方
despite everything else?
幸福地生活在一起吗？
I think what we both need to focus on
我认为我们首先应该考虑的
is how we can be happy together.
就是怎样才能幸福地生活在一起
Right.
对
This is something we should discuss properly.
我们应该好好谈谈
Sorry.
对不起
I am worried…
我担心…
about my ED.
我的勃起问题
I know in my head…
我知道…
that our relationship is not just about the sex.
性生活不是婚姻的全部
I know it,
我懂的
but a part of me felt like I was a failure.
但心里还是觉得有点自卑
And
而且
we have one more thing we need to talk about.
我们还有一件事要谈
Whether or not we will have kids.
我们以后会不会要小孩
I know sex isn't the only way to have children,
我知道除了性爱 还有其他办法怀孕
but those other methods are probably really tough.
但那些办法很辛苦
Besides,
除此之外
I felt like we've never even talked about whether we want to have kids or not.
我觉得我们从没好好谈过 想不想要小孩
I want you to be honest
我希望你能告诉我
and tell me how you really feel about having kids and my ED.
关于我的阳痿 还有生孩子的事 你到底是怎么想的
I will be honest with you too.
我也会告诉你我的真实想法
What do you think?
你觉得呢？
Ichiko?
小一？
Are you okay?
没事吧？
I UNDERSTAND WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
（我懂你的意思）
I WANT TO HAVE THIS TALK TOO.
（我也想好好谈谈）
THANKS FOR COMING BACK.
（谢谢你能回来）
You'll catch my cold.
会传染给你的
I don't mind if I do.
传染了也没关系
Okay.
好
You're going back?
你还要走？
I left my clothes and suitcase there.
衣服和包还在那边
And it feels like if I stay, we might eventually go back to the way things were.
而且我觉得如果留下 一切又会恢复成老样子
So I'm going back.
所以我走了
Get well soon, Ichiko.
早日康复 小一
Isn't it okay if things eventually went back to the way things were?
恢复成老样子难道不好吗？
Is that a bad thing? Otoyan.
那样不行吗 二也？
Mama!
妈妈
Hiro.
小宏
We're back.
我们回来了
Welcome back.
回来啦
Is it okay for you to be up?
你不用卧床休息吗？
Yeah. I'm feeling much better today.
今天感觉好多了
Hiro. Let's wash our hands first.
小宏 先洗手
Come on. Let's wash our hands.
来 我们去洗手
Come on. Okay, okay.
好 来吧
You can play after you wash your hands.
洗完手再玩
After you wash your hands.
先洗手
-Thank you. -Sure.
谢谢你
Here.
给
Thank you.
谢谢
You got some color back in your face.
你的脸色好些了
I think I'm almost back to normal.
我觉得我已经差不多好了
I think I can take Hiro to school and pick him up if I keep feeling like this.
如果能继续保持 那我就能接送小宏了
That's good. But don't force yourself.
太好了 不过别勉强
Let me know if you need help.
需要帮忙就告诉我
Sure. Thanks.
谢谢
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Well…
那个…
There's something I want to talk about.
我有件事想跟你说
What is it?
什么事？
Well…
是这样…
There's someone I want to say goodbye to
在搬去国外前
before we move abroad.
我想和一个人道别
Who?
谁？
The man…
那个…
I stabbed with a kenzan flower base.
被我用剑山刺伤的男人
Is that okay?
可以吗？
I don't understand.
我搞不懂
Why do you feel the need to?
为什么需要和他道别？
And why are you asking me?
而且 问我又算怎么回事？
I know it's selfish and egotistical of me.
我知道这么做很自私
I know.
我知道
But I want to apologize in person for stabbing him.
但我还是想当面向他道歉
I want to end things cleanly
我想先把事情好好解决
before starting over again.
然后再重新开始新生活
I asked you because there's nothing for me to hide anymore.
之所以问你 是因为我现在没有什么好隐瞒的
Of course
当然
I could have met him without telling you.
我可以不告诉你 直接去见他
I could have, but…
可是…
Haven't you already decided to do it?
你已经打定主意要去见他了吧？
This is you informing me,
你只是在通知我
not asking for a discussion.
并不是征求同意
And you're telling me this because you already know I can't say no.
你之所以告诉我 是因为你知道我不能拒绝
You can go see him.
你可以去见他
If that will make you feel better.
只要能让你安心
Of course I'm not happy about it.
你去见他 我当然不开心
But I'm also not angry about it.
但我也没有生气
I trust you, Mitsuki.
我相信你 美月
No.
不
I want to trust you.
我想相信你
LEARN ABOUT THE SEA WITH SEAFLOS
（和Seaflos一起探索海洋）
Hello?
喂？
Hello? Ichiko?
喂？小一吗？
You never answer the phone.
你总是不接电话
Sorry, I've been busy.
对不起 我最近很忙
Can you tell Otoya the thing was delivered?
你能转告二也东西到了吗？
The thing?
东西？
That thing. The kettle. I got it.
就是那个水壶 我收到了
And the rice crackers.
还有米饼
I called him, but it didn't go through.
我给他打过电话 但打不通
Okay.
好的
But Mom, you called Otoya at this time?
但是妈妈 你这个时间给他打电话？
You shouldn't. He'll be working or on his way home.
别这样啊 他正工作呢 不然就在回家的路上
But I want to say my thanks.
但我想跟他说谢谢
You can just send a message.
发个短信就行了
I've told you so many times that we can't always pick up since we're both working.
我都说多少次了 我们俩都要工作 有时没办法接电话
Okay.
好
I'll tell him you said thanks when he comes home.
等他回来我告诉他
Thank you.
多谢了
Bye.
挂了
No. He's not coming home. He left the house.
他才不会回来 他离家出走了
As if I can say that.
这哪能说呀
Hello?
喂？
Hello, Ichiko?
喂？一子
Sorry for calling you so suddenly.
抱歉突然打给你
Were you working?
在忙吗？
No, it's okay.
不 没关系
What about you? Are you outside?
你呢？在外面吗？
I'm going home after having a barbecue with people from school.
和同学吃了烧烤 现在正要回家
You sure like to party.
开派对呀
Did you have fun?
好玩吗？
The sunset on the river beach was so beautiful.
河边的夕阳太美了
And
于是
it made me want to see you.
突然很想见到一子
Hello?
喂？
Otoya.
二也
Thank you for meeting me today.
谢谢你今天来见我
It's selfish of me, but I wanted to apologize in person.
虽然很自私 但我想当面向你道歉
I'm very sorry for doing and saying such horrible things
之前说了很过分的话 做了很过分的事情
to you.
真的很抱歉
It's okay.
没关系
I'm sorry too.
我也很抱歉
Was your injury okay after I left?
你的伤后来好了吗？
Physically, it healed pretty fast.
外伤很快就好了
But it's still bothering me psychologically.
但心里一直有个疙瘩
The words you said before you left had a bigger effect on me than I expected.
你临走前说的话 威力比我预想的还要大
It might not be much help for me to say this.
现在说这些可能于事无补
But that's not what I want now.
但我已经不那么想了
I am really sorry
打扰了你的生活
for creating problems in your life.
给你添了麻烦 我真的很抱歉
I want to take back what I said and I hope you'll recover.
我想收回当时说的话 希望你能好起来
Your heart and your body
你的身心
is obviously your own.
都是属于你自己的
Thank you.
谢谢
But you didn't create any problems.
但你并没有给我添麻烦
If there are issues in my marriage,
如果我的婚姻出现问题
that is a problem between me and her.
那就是我们夫妻间的问题
You are still the same.
你还是老样子
What part?
怎么？
Your marriage is the center of your world.
你总把婚姻放在第一位
You think so?
是吗？
Yeah, it always was.
是啊 一直是这样
It was why you started and ended our affair.
发生外遇、结束外遇 都是因为这个
I think you really cherished and trusted your wife.
你真的很珍惜 也很信任你的妻子
That is why you had an affair with me.
所以你才出轨的
I couldn't forgive that…
我没办法原谅这一点…
even though I'm just a third party.
虽然我只是个第三者
I need to apologize to you too.
我也必须向你道歉
I thought I could be of help to you.
我以为自己能帮到你
But that was probably my own misunderstanding.
但我可能太一厢情愿了
I got carried away without truly understanding your pain.
我没有真正了解你的难处 就自以为是地英雄救美
Saying things like I can help you and don't stress yourself out.
说什么“我会帮你的”、“别勉强自己”
I was probably the one who created problems in your life.
是我打扰了你的生活 给你添了麻烦才对
I'm sorry for doing that.
真的很抱歉
Otoya, I'm also trying to rebuild my family with my husband.
二也 我也在尝试挽回我的婚姻
I did something stupid.
我做了件傻事
But I don't think I would have made it this far if we never did what we did.
但如果没有这段经历 我觉得我撑不到今天
You really saved me back then.
那时候 你真的救了我
I'm grateful for that.
我很感激
I'm sorry.
对不起
I paid you back with pain.
我恩将仇报 伤害了你
Pain…
伤害…
You're probably right.
或许吧
Otoya,
二也
you know,
其实
I'm pregnant.
我怀孕了
But don't worry. It's my husband's.
别怕 是我丈夫的
We haven't slept together for a while, right?
我们很久没发生关系了 对吧？
So relax.
别担心
I see.
这样啊
Mitsuki.
美月
I might not have the right to say this to you, but…
可能我没资格说这种话 但…
Be happy.
祝你幸福
Otoya.
二也
You too.
也祝你幸福
Of course.
当然了
Then, I'll go now.
那我走了
Bye.
再见
OTOYA AIHARA
（相原二也）
Who is it?
是谁打来的？
Why don't you pick up?
怎么不接？
Sorry, I'm going to take this.
抱歉 我得接一下
Hello?
喂？
Hello, Ichiko?
喂？小一
Sorry, were you working?
对不起 打扰你工作了吗？
It's okay. Did something happen?
没关系 有什么事吗？
No, I just wanted to talk to you.
没有 就是想和你谈谈
Is it okay if I come back home for a bit today?
我今天能回一趟家吗？
Sorry it's so sudden.
抱歉这么突然
It's okay.
没事
It's your home too.
这也是你的家
You can come back without asking.
你想回就能回
Thank you.
谢谢
I'll see you later then.
那待会儿见
-Bye.
-好
Thanks for waiting.
久等了
Your husband?
你丈夫吗？
He said he's coming home today.
他说今天会回家
For forever?
今后不走了？
I don't know. It might be just for today.
不知道 可能只是今天吧
And you're okay with that.
这样也可以
It's like you're being pushed around by him.
感觉他把你呼来喝去的
Well,
这个嘛…
it was also my fault.
我也有错
Your fault for having sex with me at the brothel?
错在去风俗馆和我发生了关系？
Ichiko.
一子
You said you did it for yourself,
你说过 你是为了自己才那么做的
of your own free will and you have no regrets.
说你心甘情愿 一点也不后悔
So isn't changing your mind like this so cringe?
现在变成这样 岂不是很矫情？
But you know,
可是
marriage isn't so simple.
夫妻关系是很复杂的
Isn't so simple, huh?
复杂吗？
Like,
你是说
"You won't understand because you're not married"?
“因为你没结过婚 所以你不懂”
I think there are things that even I get.
我未必就那么无知吧
Sorry.
抱歉
I'm the one who is acting cringe.
表现得矫情的人是我才对
Ichiko.
一子
Let's go somewhere.
我们去个地方吧
Somewhere?
哪里？
Bubble tea?
珍珠奶茶？
Not that.
不是那个
You know what I mean.
你懂我的意思
Sorry.
抱歉
It's because I'm seeing you like this, right?
是因为我这样和你见面 对吧？
I really can't right now.
我现在真的不行
I have to go home.
我要回家了
Okay.
好吧
I'm sorry.
对不起
See you.
再见
Ichiko.
一子
Will you get back together with your husband?
你要和你丈夫和好吗？
I don't know.
不知道
But I'm going to try.
但我会努力尝试
I want to try.
我想试一试
Ichiko.
一子
Am I not an option for you?
你不能考虑我吗？
I want to know more about you.
我想进一步了解你
And want you to know more about me.
也希望你能更加了解我
This is the first time
这是我第一次
I've felt this way.
有这样的感觉
So I'm super confused.
所以我很困惑
But
但是
I think
我想
I really like you after all.
我是真的喜欢你
Thank you,
谢谢你
Rei.
礼
I'm really happy that someone like you would like me like that.
你这样的人会喜欢我 我真的很开心
But I'm sorry.
但是对不起
The one I want to spend my life with is
我想与之共度一生的人
my husband.
是我的丈夫
Okay.
这样啊
Thank you for being straight with me.
感谢你直言相告
Ichiko.
一子
Good luck.
祝你好运
Thank you.
谢谢
You too.
你也一样
Take care of yourself.
多保重
Bye.
再见
I'm home.
我回来了
Welcome back.
你回来啦
You cleaned. You did your best, didn't you?
家里好干净 你努力打扫了吧？
Kind of.
还行吧
I'll help you cook.
我来帮你做饭吧
No, it's okay.
没关系的
I'm not a guest, you know.
我又不是客人
That's right.
那倒是
-Let's eat.
-我开动了
-It's delicious. -Yeah. Delicious.
-好吃
And you? What have you been eating?
二也 你最近都在吃什么？
Anything I can make on one electric stove.
用电炉做饭 凑合着吃
But I don't think I ate enough vegetables. I kept getting mouth sores.
但好像蔬菜吃得不够 总有口腔溃疡
Yeah, me too.
我也是
It's been too long since I've made more than three dishes.
我好久没做过超过三道菜了
Thank you, Ichiko.
谢谢你 小一
Ichiko.
小一
Can we talk?
我们能谈谈吗？
What?
怎么了？
Ichiko.
小一
I want to move back…
我想搬回来…
and live together with you again.
继续和你一起生活
Honestly, I'm still worried about the sex.
说实话 我还在为性生活的事担心
And it feels like I'm being selfish for wanting to live together.
而且想和你一起生活 感觉我很自私
But that's what I really want.
但这是我真正想要的
Of course I will respect your wishes.
当然我会尊重你的意愿
What do you think?
你是怎么想的？
What do you want?
你想要什么？
Give me a second.
等一下
I'm gathering my thoughts.
我来组织下语言
Eat, Otoyan. It will make it easier for me to talk.
你吃吧 二也 这样我说起来容易些
I also want you to come back home.
我也希望你回家
I was thinking about
我们分开的这段时间
what makes a marriage
我一直在想
the entire time we were apart.
婚姻的本质是什么
But I still haven't found an answer.
可我还没找到答案
We might have been stuck circling the same spot in the past
以前我们在同一个地方兜来转去
and will do that even in the future.
以后或许还会这样
But…
但是…
But?
但是？
We were serious, weren't we?
我们是认真的 不是吗？
And
而且
we never broke up.
我们从没放弃这段婚姻
About our sex life,
至于性生活
I still don't have a solution for it.
我现在还没有解决的办法
And coincidentally you have an issue now.
正好你现在又遇到了障碍
But it first started with my lack of a sex drive.
但这件事的源头 是因为我缺乏性欲
So…
所以…
I think the things we've been through recently
我觉得我们这段时间的经历
were necessary for us in our relationship.
是这段婚姻中的一个必要过程
Otoyan.
二也
I have a suggestion.
我有个提议
What is it?
什么提议？
Want to try having a baby?
我们尝试要个孩子吧？
We'll probably need fertility treatments.
我们可能需要接受生育治疗
And it will be hard, so I don't know if it will work out.
这个过程会很艰难 所以我不知道能不能成功
But no matter what happens,
但无论发生什么
I think it will help us move forward.
这都能帮助我们继续前进
Ichiko.
小一
I had thought about it too.
我也这么考虑过
I want to try.
我想尝试
You sure?
真的吗？
Yeah.
真的
Okay.
好
Let's eat.
快吃吧
And six months later…
六个月后…
we got a divorce.
我们离婚了
THIS IS A WORK OF FICTION.
（本故事纯属虚构）
Subtitle: Annie Chen
字幕翻译：纪小敏